AICHAOUI OUSSAMA

Full Stack Developer & Information System Administrator

Aïn Taya, Algiers, Algeria • ouss.aich2022@gmail.com • +213 792333219

PROFILE

I am a Full Stack Developer and Information System Administrator with over 6 years of experience in software engineering. I excel at solving complex problems and delivering innovative solutions to enhance processes and drive business growth.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SARL ETPB CHEMRINE

Full-Stack Developer

2020-2022

- Developed a PHP (Laravel) web platform, increasing backend efficiency.
- Created engaging front-end experiences with React.js and SCSS.
- Built RESTful APIs for mobile app integration and real-time data updates.
- Integrated Twilio for SMS notifications and Google Maps for location services.
- Ensured security during deployment and conducted unit and integration testing.
- Designed and optimized MySQL databases and documented APIs for future reference.

DJEZZY

Database Engineer

2018-2019

2019-2021

2016-2016

- Conducted interviews to gather project requirements for managers.
- Analyzed information flow to identify inefficiencies.
- Developed a MySQL database for project management tasks.
- Built a web app using PHP, Bootstrap, CSS, and jQuery for project managers.
- Secured applications with access rules to protect sensitive data.

EDUCATION

CHAMBER OF COMMERCE AND INDUSTRY C.A.C.I AND I.TE.E.M

Master's Degree in Computer Science: Information System

CHAMBER OF COMMERCE AND INDUSTRY C.A.C.I

Senior Technician in Computer Science: Databases

Camian Tanknisian in Camandan Caianaa

SKILLS

- Frontend: HTML, CSS (Bootstrap, Tailwind, SCSS), JavaScript (Angular, React, Next, Jest)
- Backend: PHP (Laravel), Node.js (Express), SQL, MongoDB, Delphi
- Mobile Development: React Native
- RDBMS: MySQL, MongoDB, SQL Server
- Tools & Frameworks: Git, Docker, Jest
- Modeling Methodologies: UML, Merise
- Wireframing & Design: Figma, Adobe Illustrator

LANGUAGES

English: ProficientFrench: ProficientArabic: Native